[SPEAKER_03]: I went across to the cigar store where the players hung out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Nobody knew me.
[SPEAKER_03]: At all.
[SPEAKER_03]: And all these players' wives, they really give me a rough time.
[SPEAKER_03]: But when the season was over, just the day before the season was over, I called them kids all in.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I said, now look,
[SPEAKER_03]: I told them the reason that day, what I'd done.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, I did it for your own benefit.
[SPEAKER_03]: As you guys got in the playoffs, you made a little extra money.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, if I'd have let you guys went along, you'd all been mad at each other.
[SPEAKER_03]: One of you would have come up with all the money.
[SPEAKER_03]: The other guys wouldn't have had any.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, all your wives would have been on me for letting you gamble and all that sort of stuff.
[SPEAKER_03]: I went to the owner and he owned the,
[SPEAKER_03]: His name was Hawkins, I believe, and he owned the radio station.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wanted me to come back the next year, and I knew.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, I wouldn't come back to this town and manage this ball club if you give me your radio station.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, I've had it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, Leo Miller was a good friend of mine.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wanted to coach in Annapolis, so I signed with him.
[SPEAKER_03]: went to Indianapolis in 1940.
[SPEAKER_03]: But then I got tired of that and quit.
[SPEAKER_03]: I just came on back home.
[SPEAKER_03]: They wanted me to come over and take a job over here at Acme Lease where they make moldings for automobiles and all that stuff.
[SPEAKER_03]: Miss Gracie, the general manager of the plant,
[SPEAKER_03]: Said if I'd come over and start a ball club for him, he'd make me a supervisor.
[SPEAKER_03]: Within less than a year, I was night superintendent of that plant, and I stayed with him 20 years.
[SPEAKER_02]: What was the name of the plant again?
[SPEAKER_02]: Acme Lease.
[SPEAKER_03]: And where is that in, uh... That was here in Muncie.
[SPEAKER_03]: They're, they're now, they've moved out of Muncie and they've gone to Cullom, Alabama.
[SPEAKER_02]: Labor problems.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, we had labor trouble there.
[SPEAKER_02]: So you stayed there?
[SPEAKER_02]: 20 years, stayed with them.
[SPEAKER_02]: That'd be from 1941?
[SPEAKER_03]: 1940 till I retired.
[SPEAKER_02]: 1960?
[SPEAKER_02]: 60.
[SPEAKER_03]: When did Acme Lease move out, Mom?
[SPEAKER_03]: When did Acme Lease, when did I retire?
[SPEAKER_01]: In 61.
[SPEAKER_03]: 61, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was 41, I think.
[SPEAKER_03]: Anyway, it was just 20 years.
[SPEAKER_01]: You quit baseball before Robin was born.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I know.
[SPEAKER_01]: Robin born in 40.
[SPEAKER_03]: I quit in 40.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the fellow that we met here.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was born in 40.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he's the only one that never saw me play.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah, he mentioned that.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, have you kept up your interest in baseball after your...
[SPEAKER_02]: retirement from the game?
[SPEAKER_03]: A little bit, not like... Nobody I know anymore.
[SPEAKER_03]: I used to go to Cincinnati and Chicago and used to go to Annapolis quite a bit when I knew a lot of the fellas, but now all the fellas are all dead or too old.
[SPEAKER_03]: They don't... All young guys.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know nobody.
[SPEAKER_03]: For me to go to St. Magnus and watch a ballgame, I can't do it.
[SPEAKER_03]: Is that right?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: When I go to Cincinnati, I'd go down in the dugout and sit down with the players.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh.
[SPEAKER_03]: Talk to them, but I couldn't stand that.
[SPEAKER_02]: You mean it's uncomfortable, or you just want to be with the players?
[SPEAKER_03]: I just don't get no kick out of it for some reason or another.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're watching on the TV?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I watch World Series on TV.
[SPEAKER_03]: Once in a while, I'll watch a
[SPEAKER_03]: Monday night game or Saturday game.
[SPEAKER_03]: But outside of that, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_03]: I played too much tennis.
[SPEAKER_03]: Did you read the sporting news much?
[SPEAKER_03]: Don't even take the sporting news anymore.
[SPEAKER_03]: You did take it?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh yeah, I took it for years.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I just quit.
[SPEAKER_02]: The game's changed a good bit since your day.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh yeah, yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: Do you like some of these changes?
[SPEAKER_02]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's a lot of changes they've made I don't like.
[SPEAKER_03]: What are some of them?
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, one of them is this designated hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: That's the craziest thing I ever heard of.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's going to lengthen the careers of some players.
[SPEAKER_02]: Suppose they'd had that in Ty Cobb or Speaker's Day or Eddie Collins.
[SPEAKER_02]: They'd have gone on and played another ten years and made some more records.
[SPEAKER_03]: Or Ruthie.
[SPEAKER_03]: It bothered, to me, to me, you work around.
[SPEAKER_03]: Don't give a manager the opportunity to do the things he wants to do.
[SPEAKER_03]: You can work around and get a pitcher up there to hit, but if you've got to designate a hitter, you can't do that.
[SPEAKER_03]: That pitcher stays there and rests and this other guy comes up and hits for him.
[SPEAKER_03]: It takes a lot of the game away, the scientific part of the game.
[SPEAKER_03]: A lot of times you can work around and walk a guy to get to a pitcher
[SPEAKER_03]: And of course, on the other hand, there's a lot of good hitting pitchers.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I'm sure that some of them...
[SPEAKER_03]: I'm sure that some of them resent that.
[SPEAKER_03]: We had a couple of pretty good hitting pitchers.
[SPEAKER_03]: Ted Lyons was a good hitting pitcher.
[SPEAKER_03]: Thurston was a good hitter.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't think the National League will ever adopt it.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't think.
[SPEAKER_02]: My objection is it distorts the records.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're so much interested in records, you know.
[SPEAKER_03]: To me, it does something to the game.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, it changes the game, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've noticed one thing.
[SPEAKER_03]: That these, of course, it's more of a business now.
[SPEAKER_03]: Most of all these players have got lawyers negotiating salaries for them and all that sort of stuff.
[SPEAKER_03]: That part of it's changed considerably, where we used to do our own negotiations.
[SPEAKER_02]: You didn't send your agent to talk to Grabner, did you?
[SPEAKER_01]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: And then on the other hand, to me, it just seems to me like a player is looking for help all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: The pitcher's out there pitching.
[SPEAKER_03]: If he gets some little jammies, he's looking for help.
[SPEAKER_03]: There's always pitchers come in.
[SPEAKER_03]: When I played, while you went out there,
[SPEAKER_03]: you better make up your mind, you're going to pitch that ball again.
[SPEAKER_03]: And if a guy got hurt, he had to get hurt awful bad to not play.
[SPEAKER_03]: Now if a guy gets a little bump, he's out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I've noticed that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Personally,
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't think, I like to see a guy get all they can get, but honest to God, to me, they ain't a ballplayer living worth the money they're getting.
[SPEAKER_03]: Really.
[SPEAKER_02]: I would think players who played in your time would feel kind of disturbed about the money and the attitudes of these modern players.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, it don't bother me any.
[SPEAKER_03]: I mean, I can understand
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I played right side of Shaw.
[SPEAKER_03]: I did all the catching.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was making $35,000 a year.
[SPEAKER_03]: Right there at the end.
[SPEAKER_03]: As a player.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I was making five.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was one of the very few that ever made that much money in Chicago.
[SPEAKER_03]: Collins might have.
[SPEAKER_03]: With Comiskey paying the bill.
[SPEAKER_03]: In fact, Shaw came to me when he was managing.
[SPEAKER_03]: Wanted to know if I was making enough money.
[SPEAKER_03]: He offered to go at the front for me, and I told him I was happy.
[SPEAKER_01]: Forget it.
[SPEAKER_03]: But, down to my heart, there ain't nobody worth the money they claim they're making, if they're making it.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I've got no reason to think that they don't make it.
[SPEAKER_02]: Troubles me is attitudes of players, too.
[SPEAKER_02]: They don't seem to care too much about the game.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now, what about attitudes in your team?
[SPEAKER_03]: You know what brought all that in?
[SPEAKER_02]: The colored people.
[SPEAKER_03]: You just, look, they resented.
[SPEAKER_03]: Like this Jackson with the Oakland A's and all them guys in a fight every day.
[SPEAKER_03]: Fighting among themselves all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: Dissension all over.
[SPEAKER_03]: I don't know how in the name of God they could win.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, you hear a player, he just, he doesn't get what he wants.
[SPEAKER_02]: quit and go into his business, you know, and it seemed to me in the old days the players just liked to play the game, or didn't care about the money.
[SPEAKER_02]: Just get out in that field was a thrill.
[SPEAKER_02]: I asked Lefty Grove, what was your greatest thrill in baseball?
[SPEAKER_02]: He said, going out to the ballpark every day.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll never forget that son of a gun, that Grove.
[SPEAKER_03]: When he first came up, he was wild.
[SPEAKER_03]: And brother, he had everybody standing on one foot back here.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'll never forget the first time I hit at him.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah?
[SPEAKER_03]: What time did you do?
[SPEAKER_03]: Holy Jesus.
[SPEAKER_03]: He threw one behind me and one down on my feet.
[SPEAKER_03]: He finally got...
[SPEAKER_03]: I can tell you a pretty good story about Walter.
[SPEAKER_03]: When I first went up, all the way up, I was there, we was in Chicago about, just about two weeks, and we went on an eastern trip.
[SPEAKER_03]: And all on that trip, all I heard was, Walter Johnson, and you're gonna have to catch again, Walter Johnson, because you hit left-handed, and Shaw kicked right-handed.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, it had me scared to death before I ever got there.
[SPEAKER_03]: So sure enough, Walter Johnson is pitching this day.
[SPEAKER_03]: And they waited until the very last minute.
[SPEAKER_03]: They said, you're catching.
[SPEAKER_03]: I said, okay.
[SPEAKER_03]: So the first time at bat, nobody on.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I hit the doggonest line drive you ever saw with a shortstop head for two bases.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I was a cocky little devil.
[SPEAKER_03]: And I come in on the bench and I said,
[SPEAKER_03]: If that's all he's got, he ain't gonna worry me, ain't he?
[SPEAKER_03]: And I sure made a mistake when I said that.
[SPEAKER_03]: The next time I went up to bat, there was a couple of guys on base, and I never saw the first three balls he threw, and I was out.
[SPEAKER_03]: I went in the bench, I said, I changed my mind.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had it.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he was a real gentleman.
[SPEAKER_02]: You think he might have let you hit that first pitch, that first time out?
[SPEAKER_03]: He was just throwing them in there, trying to get me out.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, he was just throwing them in there.
[SPEAKER_02]: I heard this, that when there were no people on base, he didn't do that much.
[SPEAKER_02]: But when he had to, he did.
[SPEAKER_03]: He did, and he had it.
[SPEAKER_03]: And you didn't have to be afraid of him, because he wasn't wild.
[SPEAKER_03]: He was right over that plate.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he really had something on that ball.
[SPEAKER_02]: I've heard it said of him that he could have won a lot more games, or he'd won a lot as it was, but he could have been even more effective if he once in a while did brush a batter back.
[SPEAKER_02]: But he would never do that because he was afraid he might hit him and he knew how fast he threw.
[SPEAKER_02]: And he just wasn't that kind.
[SPEAKER_03]: No, I don't ever remember him ever brushing.
[SPEAKER_03]: I saw him strike out 14 of us one day in Washington.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was sort of a dark day.
[SPEAKER_03]: 14.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he struck Eddie Collins out.
[SPEAKER_03]: Harry Hooper.
[SPEAKER_03]: Them guys are all pretty good hitters.
[SPEAKER_03]: Bibb Fox.
[SPEAKER_03]: 14.
[SPEAKER_02]: Were you on the game?
[SPEAKER_03]: No.
[SPEAKER_03]: I didn't catch that game.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he struck me out many times.
[SPEAKER_03]: Was it mostly fastballs that you just couldn't see?
[SPEAKER_03]: Fastballs.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he didn't...
[SPEAKER_03]: He might later on come in with a curve.
[SPEAKER_03]: Of course, you were seeing him at the end of his career, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he just threw fast balls, and he really had something on him.
[SPEAKER_03]: It was rigging away from me all the time.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He must have been quite a pitcher back in 1920, 18, 19, 20, around in there.
[SPEAKER_03]: Because he certainly could
[SPEAKER_03]: so hard when I saw him at 23.
[SPEAKER_02]: Any other players, we're about ready to wrap it up, anything, any other good stories or players or incidents that you can think of that stand out in your mind in this long career?
[SPEAKER_02]: Did you know Ruth at all, for example?
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh yeah, I knew Babe real well, yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: Any good Ruth stories?
[SPEAKER_03]: I used to have a lot of fun with him, he'd come up to play.
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd say
[SPEAKER_03]: I'd holler out the picture real loud, throw the big monkey a coconut.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, I used to have a lot.
[SPEAKER_03]: He called me Crowd Head.
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah, he was quite a guy.
[SPEAKER_03]: I saw him do something in Chicago that was unbelievable.
[SPEAKER_03]: He always played left field in Chicago on account of the sun was in right field.
[SPEAKER_03]: They never played him in sun field.
[SPEAKER_03]: In New York, they'd play him in right field.
[SPEAKER_03]: Why is this?
[SPEAKER_03]: Because of his eyes?
[SPEAKER_03]: To keep him out of the sun.
[SPEAKER_03]: To cover his eyes.
[SPEAKER_03]: But he'd come in off of left field at Comiskey Park, and he'd come in our dugout, stand down there in the dugout, and he'd eat hot dogs.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I bet that guy'd eat, well, easy, more than a dozen.
[SPEAKER_03]: You mean between innings?
[SPEAKER_03]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_03]: He'd come in your dugout?
[SPEAKER_03]: But he'd stand down in the dugout, we had a runway, a tunnel, and he'd stand down and eat hot dogs.
[SPEAKER_03]: And he's down there this day, not thinking he's going to hit that ending, but he comes up, it's his turn to hit, the way you think he did.
[SPEAKER_03]: He grabbed a fungal off our rack, a fungal stick, and went up there and he hit one nine mile out of the park.
[SPEAKER_03]: A whole number of the fungal stuff.
[SPEAKER_03]: Wasn't it illegal to use fungal bats?
[SPEAKER_01]: No, not then.
[SPEAKER_03]: He comes out of the Chicago dugout.
[SPEAKER_03]: Just grabbed a fungal and went up there and hit.
[SPEAKER_03]: He didn't go and get his own bat.
[SPEAKER_03]: He took a fungal.
[SPEAKER_03]: Oh, he was something else.
[SPEAKER_02]: I would think it would cost some common to see him come out of the other team's dugout, too.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, I'll tell you, they expected him to do it, I suppose.
[SPEAKER_03]: Well, he must have been.
[SPEAKER_03]: They was in Chicago when Miller Huggins fined him $500 for not bumping.
[SPEAKER_03]: In Chicago.
[SPEAKER_03]: Sent him home.
[SPEAKER_03]: New York.
[SPEAKER_03]: What did he do?
[SPEAKER_03]: Swung away?
[SPEAKER_03]: Swung away, hit a line drive.
[SPEAKER_03]: Hit a line drive to right field.
[SPEAKER_03]: But Huggins, they was quite right about that.
[SPEAKER_03]: Huggins fined him 500 bucks.
[SPEAKER_03]: Send him up there to bunt.
[SPEAKER_03]: He wouldn't bunt.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well... Well, did you have any... Did he tell you any stories after the tape recorder went over?
[SPEAKER_00]: Was over?
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, not too many.
[SPEAKER_02]: So there's nothing there to put on.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you asked him some questions at the end there.
[SPEAKER_02]: Uh-huh.
[SPEAKER_02]: I forgot what they were, though.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, the front porch.
[SPEAKER_02]: I asked if he knew Nick, this is Clyde Crouch now, we finished the interview, we got there about six or seven minutes after eight and it's quarter after eleven now, it's almost three hours.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's over three hours, the tape is almost three hours, it's a good two and a half hours.
[SPEAKER_02]: Little things I'd mention, he'd pick up stories very quickly that recalled to mind.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mentioned Nick Cullip as somebody we visited in Columbus.
[SPEAKER_02]: He said he knew him and he played against him in the Little World Series a couple of times and hunted alligators in Florida with a rifle.
[SPEAKER_02]: So I'll have to ask Nick Cullip about that when I see him next.
[SPEAKER_02]: Rita spent the whole time out with Mrs. Krause in the kitchen.
[SPEAKER_02]: We picked him up on the tape, but I didn't do anything because Krause's voice is so sharp and clear, it drowns everything else out.
[SPEAKER_02]: No danger of being confused with background noises.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, and really after that thing with Mrs. English, you know, Woody English and his mother.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought when she said that I was better off going into the kitchen.
[SPEAKER_00]: Except it was pretty close to us.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, there wasn't much we could do about that.
[SPEAKER_00]: That was the only place there was to go.
[SPEAKER_02]: We could have moved ourselves a little bit, but as I say, he was talking loud and clear.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I don't think you can catch that much of what we said.
[SPEAKER_02]: No, just a little background noise.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay, what's going on out in the kitchen there for three hours?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I was finding out all about their family.
[SPEAKER_02]: Anything baseball?
[SPEAKER_00]: Um, but the oldest boy traveled with his father.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, he did.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, we met the youngest son.
[SPEAKER_00]: They have been married 58 years.
[SPEAKER_02]: Married 1917, I think.
[SPEAKER_02]: Would that be right?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, that must be because she was 17 and they got married in December and he was 20 in January.
[SPEAKER_00]: when they got married.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he, I suppose the boy must have been about, I don't know, he must have been young because he was threatening to run away.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's real peculiar.
[SPEAKER_00]: The youngest one is that Ron that we met.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah, born in 1940.
[SPEAKER_02]: He had a tryout with the White Sox, but didn't make it past spring training.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, now, the next one is a boy, and he's six years older than Ron.
[SPEAKER_02]: By the way, do you mind what street we're supposed to turn on here?
[SPEAKER_00]: I thought he said next to a fire station.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think maybe we should turn this off until we find out where we are.
[SPEAKER_00]: Madison.
[SPEAKER_00]: Isn't that where we're supposed to be going now?
[SPEAKER_02]: Here's 32 here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Maybe this is the avenue or the Broadway.
[SPEAKER_02]: The highway, do you call it?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, but it's 35 we want.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is Elm.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's Madison.
[SPEAKER_00]: We go out Madison, don't we?
[SPEAKER_02]: Let's go out Madison and see what happens.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, I'm sure we came in Madison.
[SPEAKER_02]: Okay, go ahead.
[SPEAKER_02]: Next son.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, Ron was born in 1940.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, so the next is a boy and that must be Joe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Joe's in Florida.
[SPEAKER_00]: I'll tell you more of Joe later.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's six years older than Ron.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I think Helen is six years older than the boy.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then there was four years and a girl.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then I think there was four years and a boy, and then four years and another boy, if this makes sense.
[SPEAKER_00]: She had two boys, two girls, and then two boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the last two boys she got, her family was all over when she had them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, here's the sign, Ball State University.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's the travel lodge.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_02]: This must be that Wisner Street.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, this is where we turn right, right?
[SPEAKER_00]: And so Ron was our bud.
[SPEAKER_00]: They missed their father apparently.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so he was threatening to run away.
[SPEAKER_00]: and join his father.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so she finally said it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said, after she's, since then, she's kind of regretted doing it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I suppose he must have been about 11, 12, something like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because she said she wasn't sure it was a good idea to have him traveling with all those men like Eddie Collins.
[SPEAKER_00]: And she was saying something about Gleason had passed a rule that nobody could, I think it was Gleason, could have a new ball, none of the players.
[SPEAKER_00]: If they did, there would be a $50 fine.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so Eddie Collins would say to Bud, I'm going to give you, well, maybe Bud was younger at this point because he went a couple of years with his dad, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Here's a dirty old ball.
[SPEAKER_00]: Tell him, and you're going to tell me back.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't want a dirty old ball because my father has a trunk load of new ones."
[SPEAKER_00]: And she said her husband had an awful time trying to explain that remark away.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were always putting this bud up to tricks, you know, when he was traveling with them.
[SPEAKER_00]: But she
[SPEAKER_00]: One year she went down to spring training with them, took the kids out of school and went.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then as soon as school was out, she would pack up the kids and he would take an apartment or a house, wherever he was, you know, stationed or based.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they would go up there and then when he went in the road, they would pack up and come back to Indiana and then go back up and meet him again.
[SPEAKER_00]: And one time she had five of them with her.
[SPEAKER_00]: But I know when Ron was born, and Joe must have been when Joe was two, the eldest boy, their first son got married.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, there's that big a spread in the family.
[SPEAKER_02]: Of course, that Ron was born when his father was pretty old.
[SPEAKER_02]: He was 43.
[SPEAKER_02]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: What's he?
[SPEAKER_00]: He's going to be 78 in January?
[SPEAKER_02]: Born in 97.
[SPEAKER_02]: Oh, go ahead.
[SPEAKER_00]: 1907?
[SPEAKER_00]: 1897.
[SPEAKER_02]: So if Ron was born in 1940, his father would be 43.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's kind of old, I guess.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, but I mean, I was going to say, the father will be 78 in January.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, his wife is going to be 76.
[SPEAKER_00]: So she was 41 when Ron was born.
[SPEAKER_00]: She's pretty old, too.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: Mm-hmm.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, uh, there are two boys living in town.
[SPEAKER_00]: There's Ron.
[SPEAKER_02]: What time is it?
[SPEAKER_02]: Midnight, by the way.
[SPEAKER_00]: I have some oatmeal cookies there, and that's it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I guess so.
Okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, if you want anything to drink with it, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: We might find something along the road here.
[SPEAKER_00]: I think we ought to turn this off.
[SPEAKER_01]: Why?
[SPEAKER_00]: Because it's got all our other chatter on it here about finding a place to eat.
[SPEAKER_02]: We didn't find a place to eat, but we did find a place that had food.
[SPEAKER_02]: We brought some back here.
[SPEAKER_02]: Here we are in the motel.
[SPEAKER_02]: Rita's going to continue her discussion.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's all yours.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, so they have two boys in Muncie, the youngest one and the second oldest one, Ted.
[SPEAKER_00]: And Ron, the youngest, is a schoolteacher in a junior high.
[SPEAKER_00]: His wife is a schoolteacher, and they have two girls.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ted is vice president of some Marsh supermarket chain with 72 stores or something they own.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's got three boys.
[SPEAKER_00]: And two of his boys are at Tennessee Central Baptist College or something, a very fundamentalist Baptist school.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then they have one 14-year-old at home.
[SPEAKER_02]: Are they fundamentalist?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, they are.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, Grace Baptist Church they belong to, which is an independent fundamentalist church.
[SPEAKER_00]: I didn't ask.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now The girls there is Iris in the Poconos Her husband owned a howdy or hottie Meatpacking company in New Jersey
[SPEAKER_00]: But it was a family concern.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they went out of business there.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they had lived in New Jersey for 25 years.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they went up to Wilkes-Barre.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he went to Buffalo, her husband.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then he came back to Wilkes-Barre.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's working with some other meatpacking industry there.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were washed out in the flood.
[SPEAKER_00]: They had just bought a home.
[SPEAKER_00]: Now, who is this again?
[SPEAKER_00]: The daughter, Iris.
[SPEAKER_01]: Now, she must have... How many kids did they have again?
[SPEAKER_00]: I think she must have four.
[SPEAKER_00]: Iris does.
[SPEAKER_00]: And what about the parents?
[SPEAKER_00]: Boy, they were six kids.
[SPEAKER_00]: Four boys and two girls.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, uh, her one son is, uh, in law school.
[SPEAKER_00]: He went off to Vermont College.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's 26, 25.
[SPEAKER_00]: And her eldest son is 27.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's a CPA, and he's making $30,000 a year.
[SPEAKER_00]: Iris.
[SPEAKER_00]: Helen lives in North Carolina.
[SPEAKER_00]: Her husband's in the jewelry business.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think she had a boy and a girl, because the boy lives in Virginia Beach.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the girl is married to a doctor
[SPEAKER_00]: in Washington, D.C. That Iris' son is going to be a lawyer.
[SPEAKER_00]: His wife is a nigh-doctor.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or going to be.
[SPEAKER_00]: She'll get her degree in May.
[SPEAKER_00]: An ophthalmologist or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then she's got two sons.
[SPEAKER_00]: They have two sons in Florida.
[SPEAKER_00]: Bud, the eldest, and Joe, one of the youngest.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I don't know whether Bud has five boys or something.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I think Joe has one adopted.
[SPEAKER_00]: Anyway, the whole point is they have 17 grandchildren and 13 great-grandchildren.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's why they don't have any pictures around anymore.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because there's so many boys in the family.
[SPEAKER_00]: It is.
[SPEAKER_00]: Shame.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why?
[SPEAKER_00]: They don't have any pictures.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, I know, but their grandchildren want them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, but I want them, too.
[SPEAKER_01]: Well.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I'll take care of them.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, so will their grandchildren.
[SPEAKER_00]: because they can't do enough for them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They went down to North Carolina, stayed with Helen, and because they were opening another jewelry store in their chain, they were awfully busy, so they drove over to Virginia Beach to be with their grandson.
[SPEAKER_00]: And I want you to know that he drove back 850 miles, would it be, from North Carolina?
[SPEAKER_02]: It might well be, yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: He drove back in one day.
[SPEAKER_00]: He drove back from the Poconos in one day.
[SPEAKER_02]: You mean Bucky Crouse?
[SPEAKER_00]: Bucky Crouse.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's got cataracts.
[SPEAKER_00]: Had a heart attack four years ago.
[SPEAKER_00]: She's got cataracts.
[SPEAKER_01]: They look good.
[SPEAKER_00]: Eight years ago, their kids came for their 50th wedding anniversary.
[SPEAKER_00]: A cruise to the West Indies.
[SPEAKER_00]: And in two years, they'll be celebrating their 60th, and the kids are going to give them another big vacation.
[SPEAKER_00]: They are.
[SPEAKER_00]: But their kids have been very, very good to them.
[SPEAKER_00]: They all want them to stay with them.
[SPEAKER_02]: And they want... Well, I can see why.
[SPEAKER_02]: They're such nice people.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, but they'll never stay more than three weeks any place.
[SPEAKER_00]: But as she said, they've been lucky because they have their help.
[SPEAKER_00]: And they're ready to go.
[SPEAKER_00]: Although she had trouble with his mother and father.
[SPEAKER_00]: They were most uncooperative when he was in baseball.
[SPEAKER_00]: They didn't approve of it, apparently, or something.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, I asked him about that.
[SPEAKER_02]: That was one thing I did ask him.
[SPEAKER_02]: I don't know if the tape was on.
[SPEAKER_02]: I asked him, did your parents see you play?
[SPEAKER_02]: And he said, yes, both his mother and father.
[SPEAKER_02]: And we didn't get any more than that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, the thing was that when she wanted to go or something, when she just had one kid,
[SPEAKER_00]: It was always her mother's chateau, because his folks would never keep him while she went to be wherever he was.
[SPEAKER_02]: Did she go to many games?
[SPEAKER_02]: Was she a baseball fan?
[SPEAKER_00]: In the summer.
[SPEAKER_02]: They went.
[SPEAKER_02]: I mean, did she go to the ballpark?
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, they went to the ballpark, but she'd never take the kids out of school until, she'd never go until school was over.
[SPEAKER_00]: She wouldn't.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I thought you meant something had happened over there.
[SPEAKER_01]: Yeah.
[SPEAKER_00]: And, um... What?
[SPEAKER_01]: Was it my foot?
[SPEAKER_02]: You got a lot of tape to fill up there, and there's nothing else I can put on it, so you might as well talk.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't have that much more to say.
[SPEAKER_02]: You're in the three hours.
[SPEAKER_02]: One straw for your...
[SPEAKER_02]: So, she went to the ballpark.
[SPEAKER_02]: She sit with the gals, the wives that she...
[SPEAKER_01]: I didn't ask.
[SPEAKER_02]: Those are your questions.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, there's nothing else then.
[SPEAKER_02]: I bet you must have some more stories.
[SPEAKER_02]: No good baseball stories or...
[SPEAKER_02]: Talk about wives, or players, or achievement?
[SPEAKER_00]: She didn't mention any of them, except Teddy Collins.
[SPEAKER_02]: It's just family history.
[SPEAKER_02]: Well, okay, it's about half of this tape left.
[SPEAKER_02]: That means we got 45, 90, but the whole other side of this could make
[SPEAKER_02]: 135.
[SPEAKER_02]: About half of this, about 20.
[SPEAKER_02]: 155 minutes.
[SPEAKER_02]: That's about two hours and over two hours and a half.
[SPEAKER_02]: Very good.
[SPEAKER_02]: Now signing off.
[SPEAKER_02]: At quarter to twelve, Friday night, November 1, 1974, at Gray's Motel in Muncie, Indiana.